all right welcome everybody to this
assembly video tutorial in this tutorial
I'll be showing how to do some math in
assembly first of all I want to say
thank you for those who do comment on my
videos
someone did suggest for me to have the
fonts Lord bigger if you don't have high
definition so I did make the fun figure
for y'all
you're welcome alright so let's get to
the tutorial let's declare some
variables that will hold a message that
we'll use later to display items to the
screen
okay so here I'm declaring a variable
that will hold the type of operation and
we're about to perform it's going to go
right here it's replace this item right
here and then I display a message that
will display the overall information
that we're about to relate to the screen
so for example it'll say 4 plus 4 is
equal to whatever okay so let's just
play that message to the screen
you
okay so
we do here is we call the printer
function by pushing all the parameters
onto the stack in backwards order we'll
jump over to the command line and run
our program as it is right now and as
you can see it did work and we're saying
we want to do 8 plus 4 and it should
equal 12 okay so now here if you look at
this 12 you know that of course we
didn't do any actual adding to get the
result of 12 so let's go ahead and do
that now
okay so
you can see we're saying add a X
register with a DX register and store
the result inside of a X register well
this can be problematic because what
we're now doing is we're overriding the
result of the value of a X register with
12 and so when we go to display the
overall message it will say 12 plus 4 is
equal to 12 for example if I recompile
the program over here after saving the
project recompile this as 12 plus 4 is
equal to is equal to 12 which is not
true but that's only because we have
here overridden the value of the ADX
register with 12 and so the overall
statement is not true
so as a way to solve that problem we can
do something like this
and here we say move ECX with ax
now we store the value so basically we
push for onto the stack so we can do the
operation so four plus eight will now be
twelve and then we take the result of
twelve into the CX register and then we
push for back into a X register and so
if we now compile them run up program
they should say four plus eight plus
four is equal to twelve at the same time
we have to change here so it's dynamic
by changing by pushing ECX register
which of course holds the result the
final results so if we say that and we
compile this is what a nice script to
compile the program looks like
and of course to make this script and
executable all we have to do is
and then to run the program you can see
God
okay all right that's going to be it for
this tutorial join me next time we're
now to go over subtraction
multiplication and division and as
always please comment and rate and
subscribe
thank you